Yuhaini Eusope

Contact No: +65 9645 4090 - E-mail: e.yuhaini@gmail.com - Nationality: Singaporean

Banking operations specialist with 9 years' work experience in global financial institutions in Singapore and Japan. Experienced in bank functions ranging from investment banking operations to private wealth operations, serving as an effective point of contact for traders, sales and relationship managers.

Areas of Expertise/Skills

- Banking Operations
- Derivatives & FX Product Knowledge
- Process Improvement
- Issuance & Settlement Services
- IBF Qualified (Level 1) in Corporate Banking (Specialisation: Enterprise/Wholesale Banking)
- Fluent in English and Malay, Japanese (N2) and Korean (Topik II Grade 3).

Work Experience

Collateral Management and Lending Officer (Department: Global Securities Financing Operations)

Clearstream Banking S.A.Singapore

November 2015 to Present

- Oversees Triparty Collateral Management process which involves the handling of trade notifications/closures and all related collateral life cycle actions
- Trade reconciliation and customer report handling process such as exceptions, fails handling, custody actions related to the Collateral Management process
- Administer the securities lending process which includes the timely input and settlement of trades.
- Supported Sales team in handling customer queries related to the Triparty Collateral Management services and lending services

Securities Administrator (Department: Issuance and Distribution Services)

Clearstream Banking S.A.Singapore

April 2012 to November 2015

- Evaluated eligibility of prospectuses and term sheets for international and domestic issues based on Terms & Conditions
- Mitigated operational risks by strictly enforcing control measures and procedures.
- Supported the firm to fulfil its regulatory obligations through timely investigation on all suspect cases flagged by Compliance screening tools.
- Key member of team for new client service offering to set up security codes for Taiwanese securities in Taiwan domestic market.
- Developed expert knowledge in assessing prospectuses and termsheets.
- Maintained perfect record in client servicing, experiencing 0 claim from customers, contributing to high service level delivered by team.
- Led training for an electronic ISIN- application system to new client as part of client on-boarding process.

FX Operations (Contract Hire)

Goldman Sachs Japan

October 2010 to March 2011

- Liaised with institutional counterparties for trade confirmations.
- Ensured trades were accurately booked, with a keen eye for identifying discrepancies.
- Rectified discrepancies in trade bookings through direct liaison with traders, eliminating errors in settlement
- Established excellent working relationships with client-facing traders despite operational back-end role.
- Developed an understanding of working with local Japanese stakeholders.

Derivatives Client Services (Department: Global Markets and Investment Banking)

Merrill Lynch Global Services Pte Ltd

July 2008 to December 2009

- Part of key task force in charge of liaising with back-office of institutional clients on derivatives trade settlement issues.
- Led team of 3 to spearhead migration of Australian trading desk servicing from Japan office to Singapore.
- Minimized trade discrepancies and resolved them efficiently by collaborating with front office, trade support and finance teams.
- Integral point of contact for middle office, finance and external counterparties.
- Participated in 2 global UATs to enhance working procedures through system improvements
- Ensured smooth transition by overseeing and implementing new workflows and documenting manuals for transfer of work functions.
- Improved system interface to make information more efficiently available to users, reducing daily processes by 1 man-hour.

Cash Control Analyst (Department: Global Markets and Investment Banking)

Merrill Lynch Global Services Pte Ltd

July 2007 to July 2008

- Reconciled nostro accounts, ensuring funds received are applied accordingly.
- Minimized exceptions and managed them in a methodical manner.

Operations Analyst (Global Wealth Management)

Merrill Lynch Global Services Pte Ltd

July 2006 to July 2007

- Executed client requests accurately and in a timely manner, acting as critical liaison for internal clients in client-facing roles.
- Acquired expert knowledge of private banking, remittance and payment processes.

Education

2014 Operations Certificate Programme (OCP)

ICMA Executive Education in Brussels, Belgium

2010 Advanced Intensive Japanese Programme

The Yamasa Institute, Okazaki (Aichi Prefecture) Japan

2006 Bachelor of Engineering (Mechanical) Honours

National University of Singapore